Joe Wojak

Mobile: 917-710-2416email: jwojak@gmail.com

• LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/joewojak</u>

• Website: https://github.com/jwwojak/jwwojak.github.io

I'm a technical writer with experience in creating documentation for external customers and internal engineering teams. I've managed large, established documentation libraries and created original documentation for new systems and services. My writing philosophy is to treat documentation like code. This means writing with open-source systems that accommodate community input and help reduce the documentation burden on developers.

Work Experience

Senior Technical Writer Spotify 2017–2022 Amplify R&D New York City

- Wrote developer-facing documentation for Spotify's internal system architecture. Content improved understanding among engineering teams about using internal services and how Spotify ad serving systems worked.
- Wrote and revised training tutorials for engineers. Changes improved accuracy, trust, content adoption, and reduced confusion.
- Created *The Spotify Technical Writing Handbook*, a writing and style guide for developers. Guide designed to help standardize writing style and organization in Spotify's internal documentation system.
- Revised and managed company glossary. Changes improved content organization, definitions, standards for inclusion, and added a search feature.
- Recorded tutorial videos about how to write and use Spotify's internal documentation system.
- Helped create a technical writing guild. The guild coordinated writing projects and promoted technical documentation at Spotify.
- Writing tools: MkDocs, Markdown, JIRA, Trello, GitHub, Confluence, Coda, Loom (video), Google docs.

Senior Technical Writer

Adobe Systems

2015-2017

Audience Manager

New York City

- Returned to Adobe to write and manage documentation for Audience Manager. Efforts brought neglected documentation up-to-date, added API content, and eliminated issue backlog.
- Created and organized documentation for the Marketing Cloud ID Service and the Marketing Cloud Device Co-Op. Efforts reduced support demands and allowed customers to work with these systems in a self-service manner.
- Mentored and collaborated with a junior technical writer based in Bucharest, Romania. Efforts prepared him to take my role after leaving Adobe.
- Writing tools: XMetaL, Oxygen (DITA authoring systems), GitHub, Confluence, Google docs.

Senior Technical Writer

Tapad

2013-2017

New York City

- First technical writer hired. Wrote documentation for Tapad's probabilistic, cross-device ad targeting system. Documentation helped client support teams create targeted ad campaigns for external clients.
- Worked with engineers to write API, Android, and iOS documentation.
- Writing tools: Confluence, Google docs.

Technical Writer

Demdex/Adobe Systems

2011-2013

- First technical writer hired. Demdex was a data management platform (DMP) acquired by Adobe. Documentation helped advertisers create, segment, target, and deliver ads to online audiences.
- Worked with engineers to write API, Android, and iOS documentation.
- Writing tools: Confluence, Google docs.

Education and Certifications

- MA, US History, University of Mississippi
- BA (Magna Cum Laude), History, University of Missouri

Writing Systems

• Methodology: Written work follows Darwin Information Typing Architecture (DITA) documentation standards.

• Technologies: HTML editors, DITA/XML systems (Oxygen, XMetaL), Markdown, GitHub, MkDocs, Stack Overflow.

• Others: Confluence, Coda, Loom (videos), LucidChart, Google (docs, slides, sheets), JIRA, Trello, Slack.

Military Service

United States Army, Ft. Bragg, NC, honorable discharge.